HADEN WATNE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

hello@hadenwatne.com



hadenwatne.com



linkedin.com/in/haden-watne

ABOUT ME

IT professional specializing in fullstack software development for web applications.

Familiar with Agile, Angular, C#, CI/CD, CSS, Git, HTML, Java, JavaScript, JSON, LEAN, .NET, Node, PWAs, ReactiveX, SCRUM, Splunk, SPAs, SQL, TypeScript, Unit Testing, and XML.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

CCU • 2015 - 2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

CCU • 2015 - 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL SERVER 2016 - DATABASE DEVELOPMENT (MCSA)

Earned in November 2018

PROGRAMMING IN C#

Microsoft Exam 483 Earned in April 2018

PROGRAMMING IN HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, AND CSS3

Microsoft Exam 480 Earned in May 2017

NETWORKING FUNDAMENTALS

Microsoft Exam 98-366 Earned in May 2017

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR IT APPS PROGRAMMER

Progressive Insurance | Colorado Springs, CO June 2019 – Present

- Replaced a customer-facing legacy web interface with a new single-page application.
- Designed an automated analytics report read daily by 200+ leaders and developers.
- Led my team through a project-scale experiment to migrate to a new CI/CD strategy.
- Supported annual Payment Card Industry (PCI) audit and compliance efforts.
- Monitored our Production environment as part of an on-call rotation.
- Reduced waste work by streamlining my team's proactive quality monitoring process.
- Created a Splunk dashboard to share performance, stability, and completion metrics.

IT INTERN

Progressive Insurance | Colorado Springs, CO May 2018 – August 2018

- Modernized an ASP.NET application by hardening vehicle search and updating security labels.
- Updated internal documentation for multiple applications.
- Completed a 3 month-long group research project on the risks of emerging autonomous vehicles.

SERVER SUPPORT SPECIALIST

CubedHost | Online Company January 2016 – June 2019

- Connected with worldwide clients to troubleshoot server performance and configuration.
- Debugged console errors, system behavior, and software dependencies.
- Analyzed statistics to determine network congestion, resource usage, and server availability.

PASSIONS







Code Quality

End-User Privacy

Usability & Design